lain Maitland

Fullstack Developer

About

13512 Gable Street

- Detroit Michigan MI 48212 US
- (737) 226-3943
- iainmaitland.com
- imaitland
- **y** iain_maitland

Web Development

Professional

React Rust Typescript
Javascript NodeJS/Deno

GraphQL

MySql/NoSql/Postgres

DevOps

Professional

AWS Docker Git

Languages

English (Native speaker)

Interests

Art

Photography Poetry Writing

Summary

lain (he/him) hails from Manchester, England. He has a degree from the University of Cambridge, in Law and History of Art, and 5 years experience as a frontend and fullstack web developer. Before going freelance he worked as an early employee for Steem, building userfacing apps on their blockchain as it scaled to 1M+ users. While his work thus far has focused on building and scaling web applications, generally interested in continuously learning from those around him, being resourceful and making software that's clear, crafty and creative. He's an avid fan of Rust, and will seize the opportunity to use it!

Experience

Freelance 01/2020 - Present

Develop useful software for a variety of clients. Fullstack developer

Working as a lead developer with a local and remote team of graphic and product designers to implement solutions for creative and b2b software briefs for a range of clients including General Motors, Amazon, Google and Ford.

- https://hobbes.work a portfolio site for an UI/UX studio using a modern Jamstack, a customized headless CMS and a React/Typescript frontend
- https://means.tv a media streaming platform with subscription features
- A custom CRM for General Motors in React and NodeJS used at Dealerships and special events nationwide

Steemit.com 01/2018 - 01/2020

Develop applications for the Steem blockchain Fullstack Developer

Working as part of a remote agile team with 3 other developers, to develop and scale open source blockchain software (https://github.com/steemit) used by millions of users and processing millions of dollars in cryptocurrency transactions.

- Built the most popular front end (React/Typescript) for the Steem blockchain, including authorization, market trading, and cryptocurrency wallet features.
- https://steemit.com A reddit clone written in React, scaling from a few thousand to millions of users internationally
- https://signup.steemit.com/ User creation service or 'faucet', onboarded more than a million new users.
- https://wallet.steemit.com Feature rich cryptocurrency wallet including trading, exchange and withdrawal.

Quikly 01/2017 - 01/2018

Develop an administration dashboard in React Frontend Developer

Working as part of an agile team with 2 other developers, on b2b dashboard software.

- Build out a GraphQL api in Ruby-on-rails to drive the react front end.
- Advocate for Typescript adoption within the company

Penske Media Corporation

01/2016 - 01/2017

Develop public magazine websites headless CMS stack. Frontend Developer

Agile team with 2 other developers, architecting CMS backends in Wordpress and Drupal and frontends in React

- Lead pivot from traditional CMS instances to a headless model
- Drive adoption of React within the company

Education

University of Cambridge, Jesus College